PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Innovative Technical Writer with over 10-years' experience researching, writing, editing, proofreading, assimilating, cataloging, and designing technical and nontechnical documentation. Extensive experience using modern documentation approaches/tools. Extensive experience working in Waterfall and Agile SDLCs. Fluent Mandarin Chinese speaker.

SKILLS

- Technical Research
- Doc. Management
- Docs-as-code
- GitHub, Git, Markdown
- Cloud Computing
- Slack, BlueJeans, Cisco WebEx, MS Teams
- Confluence, Jira, Pivotal Tracker

- MS Office Suite, MS SharePoint, MS Visio
- Adobe FrameMaker
- Adobe Photoshop
- MadCap Flare
- Final Cut Pro
- Python (Beginner)
- C++ (Beginner)

WORK HISTORY

SENIOR TECHNICAL WRITER (Remote)

10/2021 to 2/2022

U.S. Tech Solutions (Contractor) | Jersey City, NJ

- **VMware Tanzu Team** Developed, wrote, edited, and maintained documentation for the Tanzu product family. Restructured, formatted, and standardized legacy documentation.
- Proactively communicated with PMs and engineers worldwide for feedback and distribution.
- Organized material to research and complete writing tasks.

SENIOR TECHNICAL WRITER/BUS. ANALYST (Remote)

04/2021 to 06/2021

HCL (Contractor) | Redmond, WA

- Microsoft Anti-Corruption Team Researched, communicated, and explained anti-corruption policies and initiatives of Microsoft competitors and business partners to team members to understand and implement functional demands.
- Utilized exceptional writing, editing and proofreading skills to produce engaging and error-free content.

SENIOR TECHNICAL WRITER

02/2019 to 05/2020

netPolarity (Contractor) | San Jose, CA

- Nutanix, Seattle Canaveral Team lead technical writer; primary source documentation central point of contact for 18-man engineer team. Conceptualized what developer documentation should mean and drive implementation.
- Documented REST APIs and SDKs for internal development systems.

- Implemented documentation systems and processes. Created and developed Canaveral DevOps Runbook.
- Wrote release notes and other support documentation. Peer-reviewed engineers' documentation.
- Gathered information from team meetings, product specifications, SME interviews, and direct interaction with systems.
- Identified documentation issues, analyzed information, and provided solutions to problems.

TECHNICAL EDITOR (Remote)

11/2018 to 07/2019

ALTA IT Services (Contractor) | Rockville, MD

- ManTech Govt Contractor Edited multiple documents for Application
 Cloud Migration teams on an Air Force contract to refactor monolithic, legacy
 applications for migration into both AWS and Azure environments.
- Reviewed various documents for grammar, spelling, punctuation, syntax, accuracy and compliance with quality standards.

TECHNICAL WRITER/TRAINING COORDINATOR (Remote) 08/2018 to 11/2018 U.S. Tech Solutions (Contractor) | Jersey City, NJ

- Quest Technology Management Developed training materials in conjunction with engineering staff.
- Coordinated/scheduled training for 1,100 users at different locales.
- Instructed how to install and use Multi-factor Authentication (MFA) and Mobile Device Maintenance (MDM) on end devices.
- Tracked end-user issues and escalated to Sr. IT staff as required.

LEAD TECHNICAL WRITER

06/2018 to 08/2018

Brickred Systems (Contractor) | Redmond, WA

- Microsoft Azure Stack Customer Advisory Team (CAT) central point of contact for primary source documentation.
- Researched, wrote, edited and localized content with strong customer-focus.
 Gathered data from SMEs to create workbooks, users guides, reference manuals, lab sheets, etc.
- Designed and delivered documentation across disparate styles from event handouts to highly technical whitepapers. Effectively conveyed customerfocused security concepts across all levels of expertise (developer, admin, novice).

SENIOR TECHNICAL WRITER

03/2004 to 10/2016

BEA Systems/Oracle Software R&D Center | Beijing, CHINA

- Developed, wrote, edited, and maintained documentation for the Oracle Tuxedo product family. Restructured, formatted, and standardized legacy documentation.
- Wrote REST API reference documentation for C, C#, C++, and Java developers and system admins from functional specs and SME interviews.
- Datacenter and networking technical background; can easily interact with

- engineers.
- Proactively collaborated with Oracle engineers in Beijing and New Jersey,
 Bangalore doc- infrastructure, Quality Assurance, and customers to improve documentation usability.
- Trained, developed, and supervised three Chinese local-hire technical writers.
- Developed auxiliary documentation, such as Web pages, help systems, sales training, product descriptions, etc. as needed.

EDUCATION

Certificate | Mandarin Chinese Language National Taiwan Normal University, Taipei, Taiwan

Bachelor of Science | Business Administration/Management **Towson University, Towson, MD**